Today's video is credited to Priyanka
's comment. Priyanka,
thank you for your comment. As you all know,
every day, every video on the channel
comes based on your questions, suggestions and comments. So, stay connected to the channel and
for that, like and share the video. Do
n't forget to subscribe to the channel and turn on the "All Notifications" bell so that
you can stay informed about all the latest videos. So,
let's know the information related to the
surrender value of ICICI Potential Life's Gold Plan, as per Priyanka's comment. The
surrender value in this plan is
available only when you have
paid the premium continuously for the first two years. If you have
paid the premium continuously for the first two years, then
you can surrender the policy and
you get the surrender value. To calculate the
guaranteed surrender value in the plan,
you have to multiply the guaranteed surrender value factor
by the total premium paid, that is, the base
premium you have paid. Then, you
subtract the income benefit, which is called the survival benefit in the plan.
If you use the savings wallet option, then the
balance of that amount will be credited to you.  As it is, it is available,
right? So let's take an
example to understand the
center value of ICICI Potential Life's Gold Plan. Let's
assume Mr. A,
35 years old, has
taken an ICICI Potential Life Gold Plan with an immediate income option and
wants to remain covered for 999 years.
Therefore, the policy term is 64 years.
He has taken a premium payment term of 10 years and is paying the base premium of ₹1 lakh annually.
In this case, the life cover is
12 times the annual base premium, i.e.,
₹1 lakh. The
income benefit available under the immediate income
option will be guaranteed income plus cash bonus.
To calculate the income benefit,
we need to know the rate of guaranteed income and the
rate of cash bonus. According to the example we are
considering, the guaranteed income
factor is 12.25 p.a., and the
rate of cash bonus is  That is
23.75 per cent. Now let us assume that Mr. has
completed 4 years of the policy and
after that he wants to surrender the policy
because he is paying an annual premium of ₹1 lakh. So, the
rate of high premium benefit will also be available which will be 0.25 per cent. If
you add this to the guaranteed income factor, then the
guaranteed income factor will be
12.50 per cent, which you will
multiply by 1 lakh because the
rate of income benefit and cash bonus is
also applied to the annual base premium. So, after
calculating 12.50 per cent for ₹1 lakh,
we added 23.75 per cent for 1 lakh, thus resulting in an
annual income benefit of ₹6250. If
we multiply this by four, then the
received income benefit here is 135000
or the received survival benefit. Now
comes the matter of the sender value.  See,
we have taken premium payment for 10 years,
we have completed 4 years here,
so the guaranteed surrender value factor for
premium will be 50%, right? So
how much premium will you pay in 4 years,
4 lakh at the rate of ₹ 4 lakh, right? So, after taking out 50% of 4 lakh,
we will subtract the received
income benefit of ₹ 45,000, which is the received survival
benefit, then the guaranteed
surrender value will come to 55,000, which the gentleman will get
and the policy will be closed. The
saving wallet option was not used,
hence it does not exist here.
Now the information about the cash bonnet rate is
already on our screen along with the immediate
income option, which has been
announced by the policy, you can get it on their website.
Our age is falling in the bracket of 31 years to 35 years
because
we have taken the age of 35 years and have taken the premium payment term of 10 years.  The
rate of cash bonus is being recorded here at 23.75% and the
rate of cash bonus can keep changing, it does
not remain constant for one year, the
rate of guaranteed income is 10 years, our
premium payment term here is 35 years, so our age has
come in the bracket of 31 to 35 years,
so in such a situation the rate of guaranteed income benefit becomes
12.25%, that is, to
know the guaranteed sender value, you have to
check your policy bond, in that you
get the details of all the factors, if
you want to know about the other savings wallets, then
see, the
three variants available in this plan are already available,
we have shared information about all the three, the
videos of all the three are available in the life insurance playlist, the
link is given in the description of the video,
if you watch these three videos, then
you will know about all the benefits of all the three variants, right,
you watched the video till the end patiently,
thank you very much, thank you
very much for that, understand one thing yourself and others
also  Explain that insurance is a protection,
protection is never taken incompletely and
whenever you take a plan with guaranteed income benefit
and you go to surrender,
you see a huge loss but by
default you have already received your money back,
hence you see a huge loss,
right, such plans are
not made for surrender, right, keep this thing in
mind.